FÉLIX A. COLÓN

Farmington, CT | 860.751.9440 | bpr59@protonmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/albert-colon-51156311

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Delivering Excellence in UX Design, Web Development, Production and Digital Media

Accomplished, solutions-driven **Production Manager** with 20+ years of experience in domestic and international markets driving the design, production and post-production of sales/marketing integration content across linear and digital media. Looking to transition into the Web Development field where I can apply my recently acquired knowledge via the UConn Full Stack Development Certificate program. Interested in merging my production expertise with web development as a new member of a forward thinking team.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, NodeJS, ReactJS, Adobe Creative Cloud (After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, Audition) Workfront, Avid, Final Cut Pro, CMS (Aspera, Signiant), Microsoft Office Professional (Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, SharePoint)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Full Stack Web Development | Graphic Design Management | Production & Post-Production Management | Digital Media | Video/Audio Production Design & Editing Team Leadership | Project Management | Team and Relationship Building | Timecode Calculation | Voice-Overs | Quality Assurance Sponsorship Ideation/Execution | Animation | Production | Personnel Development | Copy Editing | English/Spanish Bilingual

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ESPN, Bristol, CT 2000-2019

Production Manager | 2012-2019

Oversaw Sales Integration and editorial direction of in-show sponsorships, international networks, show animation, and toolbox packages. Led and trained a team of Producers, Editors and QC Production Assistants. Protected editorial integrity. Collaborated with Production and Customer Marketing & Sales to integrate sponsorships within content time.

Key Achievements:

- Daily supervision of all aspect of the production process including ingest, QC, design, ideation, production, animation, post-production and video formating for delivery across international networks.
- Superuser of Workfront project management tool used to manage the production and productivity metrics of all sponsor elements for ESPN international markets across five networks.
- Point of contact for production teams to resolve all issues related to materials prior and post delivery.
- Created new integration ideas, drove and connected multiple platforms, and provided a consistent voice.
- Responsible for editing of all sales sponsor content for Australian market via the use of Adobe Premiere, After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator and Audition.
- Transitioned video sales elements tracking from SharePoint to Workfront to enable local and international sales office sales tracking; improved tracking system efficiency by 85%.

Ad Sales Integration Producer II | 2010-2012

Built, trained, and managed freelance producers and vendors to produce animations, promos, and sponsor/sales elements. Executed market protection and editorial integrity. Worked with studio/remote producers, directors, and programmers.

Key Achievements:

- Partnered with out-of-house production companies to develop special animations for the 2006 and 2010 World Cup.
- Spearheaded the production of a promo campaign for a studio show and the show's main sponsor Honda; solicited an outside production company to design and produce the spots and ultimately deliver 30-second promo spot.
- Proactively identified issues impacting individual networks and developed solutions; developed strategic responses by reviewing programming, production, and sales guidelines in advance or reacting to on-air situations.

FÉLIX A. COLÓN Page | 2

On-Air Promotions Producer | 2000-2010

Managed and produced image and tune-in promos for three international and one domestic Spanish network. Coordinated weekly voiceover sessions in English, Spanish, and Portuguese. Supported affiliates and partners with highlights, graphics, and animation. Worked with producers and associate producers to create promos and sourcing support materials.

Key Achievements:

- Earned two Bronze Telly Awards in 2006 & 2007 and a Promax Award in 2008.
- Designed, developed, and implemented new department post-production structure to optimize workload between 5 producers of 200+ promos per week.
- Created the 'look and feel' and production of sales features and presentations.
- Successfully developed and introduced a new Sales Production Manual; streamlined sales, prospective client, and sponsorship communications throughout ESPN International networks.
- Provided complex communications, editing, motion graphics, and audio mixing creative direction.
- Pitched and gained buy-in for original treatments and ideas for promos and campaigns; researched, wrote, produced, and edited on-air promos of various lengths and formats.
- Recruited and transitioned a Freelance Graphic Designer to independently managed editing within 4 weeks of training.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT, Hartford, CT **2020 Full Stack Developer Certificate**

NORTH TEXAS UNIVERSITY, Denton, TX
B.A., Radio, Television, and Film; Business Administration minor